Franklin-Bache Papers 1707-1799 Mss.B.F85.ba
American Philosophical Society
Franklin-Bache Papers
1707-1799
Mss.B.F85.ba
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Linear feet
Containing over 4 linear feet of letters and documents, the Franklin-Bache Papers comprises the second largest collection of letters and documents relating to Benjamin Franklin in the APS Library. Although the scope of the collection is broad, including materials from the time of Franklin's arrival in Philadelphia to his death, the heart of the collection documents the period of Franklin's ministry in France (1776-1785) and his diplomatic efforts to win financial and military support for the revolutionary cause, as well as less intensive coverage of his ministry in England before the Revolution. Franklin's correspondence with American and French officials, financiers (personal and otherwise), and savants provides tantalizing details on the social context of Franklin's ministry in France, his intellectual life, and his growing celebrity. Much of the correspondence documents the efforts to convince French officials early in the war to support the American cause, but there is valuable material relating to the peace negotiations as well. The collection is equally rich in personal correspondence, including a rich set of letters from Mary Stevenson Hewson, Georgiana Shipley, Catherine Ray Greene, Jane Mecom, Deborah Franklin, and a number of Franklin's other relatives. The collection is arranged chronologically.
4 linear feet
Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
Scope and Contents note
Containing over 4 linear feet of letters and documents, the Franklin-Bache Papers comprises the second largest collection of letters and documents relating to Benjamin Franklin in the APS Library. Although the scope of the collection is broad, including materials from the time of Franklin's arrival in Philadelphia to his death, the heart of the collection documents the period of Franklin's ministry in France (1776-1785) and his diplomatic efforts to win financial and military support for the revolutionary cause, as well as less intensive coverage of his ministry in England before the Revolution.
Franklin's correspondence with American and French officials, financiers (personal and otherwise), and savants provides tantalizing details on the social context of Franklin's ministry in France, his intellectual life, and his growing celebrity. Much of the correspondence documents the efforts to convince French officials early in the war to support the American cause, but there is valuable material relating to the peace negotiations as well. Particularly interesting are the numerous letters of instruction from Congress and from individuals such as Arthur Lee, Silas Deane, Robert Morris, Robert R. Livingston, and Henry Laurens. Other correspondents, notably Richard Bache and Francis Hopkinson, kept Franklin apprised of news and public opinion in America or, like Thomas Paine and Richard Price, offer insights into political currents more generally.
The personal side of Franklin's correspondence, as much as it might be considered separate from the political, is equally revealing. The collection includes numerous letters with Franklin's many female admirers and friends, including Georgiana Shipley (a cousin of the Duchess of Devonshire) and his long-time confidante Catharine Ray Greene. In the years flanking Franklin's residence in France, there is a particularly extensive set of letters from Mary Stevenson Hewson, that flesh out his experiences in London during the 1760s and early 1770s, and some valuable family letters. The earliest materials (prior to 1752) consist largely of deeds and other documents relating to the Read family, along with three letters from Franklin's mother-in-law Sarah White Read, and one from his mother, Abiah, which join approximately 30 letters between Franklin and his wife Deborah and over 70 from his sister Jane Mecom. Other family members, including his son William and grandsons Benjamin Franklin Bache and William Temple Franklin, appear.
The Franklin-Bache Papers are somewhat less rich in material relating to Franklin's scientific and intellectual pursuits, however there are excellent letters from scientific correspondents such as Joseph Priestley, the comte de Buffon, and Joseph Banks. Other miscellaneous items of interest include Franklin's pencil sketch of his garden at Passy (March 27, 1782), the drawing of pleasure boats on the Delaware River, and a profile of Franklin (after the Nini medallion) sent by Isidoro Bianchi that was drawn with electricity.
When acquired, the collection includes a number of important bound volumes, which are listed separately under the Franklin miscellaneous collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Franklin-Bache Papers were acquired from Mr. and Mrs. Franklin Bache in 1937.
Separated Materials note
Oversized items are housed at the end of the collection; extra-oversize materials are housed separately.
Related Archival Materials note
Other Benjamin Franklin Collections
Benjamin Franklin Papers
View Collection
James S. and Frances M. Bradford Collection
View Collection
Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections
View Collection
Naval History Note
The Franklin-Bache Papers contain a few letters pertaining to John Paul Jones which may be of interest to naval historians:
Jones, John Paul, 1747-1792.
Mecom, Jane Franklin. Letter to Benjamin Franklin. 1780 March 27. News of John Paul Jones. 2 pages.
Bache, Richard. Letter to Benjamin Franklin. 1781 March 28. Sending newspapers. John Paul Jones brought Franklin's letters and news. 1 item.
Jones, John Paul. Letter to Benjamin Franklin. 1781 August 8. Introducing Mr. Thomas Barclay. 1 page.
Jones, John Paul. Letter to Benjamin Franklin. 1781 December 13. News of self and of the war. 2 pages.
Early American History Note
The Papers of Benjamin Franklin are a rich source as varied and expansive as Dr. Franklin’s storied life. The Collection has been calendared, catalogued, and much of it is available online at franklinpapers.org and in printed volumes. The APS inventory in MOLE is extraordinarily detailed. The aim of this entry is not to reproduce what is already readily accessible, but to focus on material that is unavailable in printed or online sources.
Most notable are a series of bound volumes that capture different aspects of Franklin’s professional career. The bound volumes include a nearly complete record of the colonial Post Office that Franklin headed, numerous account books from Franklin’s time in England and France, and official account books of the U.S. mission in France. In addition to these bound account and ledger books, the collection also includes a copy of the earliest deed known deed for the Pennsylvania statehouse property, various sketches and drawings thought to be done by Franklin, and four large volumes of a journal of John Lindsay Crawford’s travels with the Russian Army from 1737-1739 that include large maps of Europe that Franklin kept in his library (these four volumes are separately described in MOLE under Crawford).
The Franklin Papers, along with the papers of his grandsons at the APS, provide a nearly complete picture of Benjamin’s time in France as an American ambassador to France during the American Revolution. Aside from the manuscript records from this period, the collection has a nearly complete set of account books detailing both the official and personal transactions of Franklin in France.
The APS also houses a collection of books that came from Franklin’s personal library. The library offers insight into Franklin’s own reading and intellectual life. A box of miscellaneous papers in the manuscript collection may also be of related research interest. This box includes a variety of documents that Franklin had in his possession, such as copies of newspapers that have marginalia, that are not included in the official published papers.
Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798; Bache, Richard, 1737-1811; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820; Barbé-Marbois, Francois, marquis de, 1745-1837; Benezet, Anthony, 1713-1784; Blunt, Dorothea, 1733-1809; Buffon, Georges Louis Leclerc, comte de, 1707-1788; Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Leray de, 1725-1803; Childs, Francis, 1763-1830; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789; Dumas, Charles-Guillaume-Frédéric; Franklin, Abiah Folger, 1667-1752; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774; Franklin, William Temple, 1760-1823; Franklin, William, 1731-1813; Grand, Ferdinand; Greene, Catherine Ray, 1731-1794; Hewson, Mary Stevenson, 1734-1795; Hopkinson, Francis, 1737-1791; Jay, John, 1745- 1829; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Jones, John Paul, 1747-1792; La Rochefoucauld, Louis Alexandre, duc de; Laurens, John, 1754-1782; Le Ray de Chaumont, J. (James), 1760-1841; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794; Livingston, Robert R., 1746-1813; Logan, James, 1674-1751; Lotbinière, Michael Alain Chartier de, 1723-1798; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809; Penn, William,1644-1718.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828; Price, Richard, 1723-1791; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804; Read, Sarah White, 1675-1761; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813; Shipley, Georgiana, d.1806; Shipley, Joseph, 1714-1788; Todd, Anthony, 1717-1798; Turgot, Anne-Robert-Jacques, baron de l'Aulne, 1727-1781; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835; Vergennes, Charles Gravier, comte de, 1717-1787; Washington, George, 1732-1799; West, Benjamin, 1738-1820; Business Records and Accounts; Colonial Politics; Colony and State Specific History; France--Foreign relations--United States; Miscellaneous; Pen works; Pencil works; Pennsylvania History; Philadelphia History; Postal service--United States; Printing and Publishing; Printing--France; United States--Foreign relations--France; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--French participation; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Peace
- Franklin-Bache Papers, 1707-1799; B F85.ba; 4 lin. feet
  - to Henry Hayes, 1707 April 7; Land Patent; Penn, William (Oversize X)
  - to William Davis, 1711 April 12; Deed for piece of land on High Street.; Hayes, Henry
  - to John, 1716 Dec. 10; Lease for land.; Hayes, Henry [?] and wife
  - to John Read, 1716 Dec. 11; Deed; Hayes, Henry and wife (Oversize X)
  - to John Read, 1716 Dec. 12; Deed; Hayes, Henry and wife (Oversize X)
  - to Sarah Read, 1729 Sept. 3; Deed; Philadelphia (Oversize X)
  - to Benjamin and Deborah Franklin, 1734 April 9; Lease; Read, Sarah White, 1675-1761 (Oversize X)
  - to John Crocker and Wife, Frances, 1734 April 10; Deed, 2 items in 1 folder; Read, Sarah White, 1675-1761 (Oversize X)
  - Benjamin and Deborah Franklin, 1734 April 10; Deed; Read, Sarah White, 1675-1761 (Oversize X)
  - Memorandum of Post-office accounts, 1738 June 20-1743 Dec. 14
  - Joshua Maddox's acct. with Benjamin Franklin, 1738 Dec. 7-[1741] March 24
  - Post-office accounts, 1744 April 18
  - to James Read, 1745 August 27; Franklin, Benjamin
  - Extract of will, with codicil; Jan. 18, 1749/50, 1749 Nov. 25; Logan, Jim, (James)
  - to Deborah and Benjamin Franklin, 1751 Oct. 14; Franklin, Abiah
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1751 Nov. 15; Deed; Read, John and Wife, Martha. (Oversize X)
  - Deposition, 1752 March 21; Peters, Richard.
    General note
    [see folder for 1749 Nov. 25]
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1752 March 25; Deed; Moore, Samuel Preston and Wife, Hannah. (Oversize X)
  - Extract from the inventory of James Logan, 1752 July 31; Franklin, Benjamin and Peters, Richard.
    [See folder for 1749 Nov. 25]
  - to William Smith, 1753 Nov. 27; Franklin, Benjamin
  - General Assembly Resolutions, 1757 Feb. 18; Pennsylvania.
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1758 Jan. 29; Mecom, Jane
  - 1758 Nov. 15-1775 June, Notes fournis....; Lotbinière, Michel-Alain Chartier de
  - Newport Mercury, 1758 Dec. 19 (Oversize OS)
  - Westminster Hospital. Account of 1758
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1760 March 17; Mecom, Jane
  - Extract from deed of Loganian Library, 1760 March 25 [?]
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1760 May 20; Franklin, Mary
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1760 Sept. 16; Stevenson, Mary
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1761 Feb. 9; Mecom, Benjamin
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1761 Sept. 22; [Faded letter].; Franklin, Peter
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1763 April 12; Franklin, Sally
  - Account between Benjamin Franklin and Jonathan Williams, Sr, 1763 Oct.-1774 August 10 (Oversize 1)
  - Account between Benjamin Franklin and Jonathan Williams, Sr, 1763 Oct.-1774 August 10 (Oversize OS)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Feb. 10, 17, 21; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1765 April 6; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 April 18; Holden, Lawrence
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1765 April 26; Franklin, Sarah
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 May 30; Franklin, Sally
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 August 1; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Sept. 22; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1765 Sept. 26; Ourry, L. S.
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1765 Sept. 28; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Oct. 6-13 ?; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774 (Oversize 1)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Oct. ? 9, 13; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Oct. 14; Franklin, Sally
  - Mortgage from Anthony Armbruster, 1765 Oct. 29 (Oversize 1)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Nov. 3, 7; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Dec. 30; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1765] Fall; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1766 Feb. 27; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1766 March 23, 25; Franklin, Sarah
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1766 June 27; Franklin, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1766 July; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to William Franklin, [1766?] Sept. 30; Franklin, Sarah
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1766 Nov. 8; Mecom, Jane
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1766 Nov. 24; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1766 Dec. 13; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 Jan. 12; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1767 April 23; Mecom, Catherine
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 April ? 29; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 May 1; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Margaret Stevenson, 1767 May 7; Cotes, W.
  - to Margaret Stevenson, 1767 May 9; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 May 15; Stevenson, Mary
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 May 16 or 17; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 May 16, 24; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 June 10; Franklin, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 July 3, 6; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 July 13; Royal Society of London
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 July 13; Royal Society of London
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 Oct. ? 19; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 Oct. 23; Franklin, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 Nov. 23; Norton, Lord
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 Dec. 1; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1768 Jan. 21; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1768 May 20-23; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1768 August 14; Bache, Sarah
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1768 Nov. 7; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1768 Nov. 24; Johnson, Martha
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 May 11; Franklin, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 August 31; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Sept. 1; Franklin, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Oct. 4-5; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Nov. 20; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774 (Oversize 1)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Dec. 7; Com. of Correspondence of N.J. Assembly
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Dec. 13,14; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Dec. 19; Smith, Joseph
    [see folder for 1769 Dec. 19]
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 March 1; French, Katherine
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 May; Bache, Sarah
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1770 [Before August ?]; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 August 16; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Deborah Franklin, 1770 August ? and Sept. 5; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 Sept. 25; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 Oct. 11; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 Oct. 11; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 Oct. 14; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Miss Jennings, 1771 March 21; Franklin, Benjamin
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 May 17; Franklin, Samuel
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 July 12; Todd, Miss
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 Nov. 8; Franklin, Samuel
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 Dec. 3; Bache, Mary
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 Dec. 13; Williams, G.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1771?] Dec. 16; Pringle, Sir John
  - Deborah Franklin, [1771?]; Bache, Sarah
  - Marriage license of Andrew Moore and Sarah Brown, 1772 Jan. 18
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 Jan. 20; Martin, Miss
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 Feb. 5; Bache, Mary
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 Feb. 6; London and Middlesex. Sheriffs
  - Memo, 1772 Feb. 7; Franklin, Benjamin
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 May 14-16; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 May 16; Bache, Richard
  - to Jane Mecom, 1772 May; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 June 14; Bache, Mary
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 June 30; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - Extract of will, 1772 July 25; Logan, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 Oct. 6; Bache, Richard
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 Dec. 10; Bache, Theophylact, 1735-1807
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 ?; Bache, Richard
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1772 ?; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1773 August 14; Blunt, Dorothy
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1773] Nov. 29; Blunt, Dorothy
  - A card..., 1773 Dec. 2
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1773? Sunday; Blunt, Dorothy
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1774 Dec. 24; Bache, Richard
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1774 Dec. 24; Franklin, William
  - Resolution, 1775 June; United States. Congress (Oversize X)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1775 July 14-19; Mecom, Jane
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1775 July 18; Greene, Catherine Ray
  - Commission as deputy postmaster of Philadelphia, 1775 Oct. 2; Bache, Richard (Oversize 1)
  - Precis de l'Affaire du Sieur de Lotbiniere.., 1775 Dec. 15; Lotbinière, Michel-Alain Chartier de
  - Table of rates of postage, 1776 Jan. 5; Great Britain. General Post Office (Oversize X)
  - Officer's Commission, 1776 April 19; Pennsylvania. Assembly
  - Letter to the Council of the House of Rep. of N.J, 1776 June 22; Franklin, William, 1731-1813 (Oversize X)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776 July 3; Greene, Catherine Ray
  - to Benjamin Franklin and James Wilson, 1776 July 6; Yeates, Jasper
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776 August 6; Franklin, Elizabeth
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776 Oct. 1; Greene, Catherine Ray
  - Lottery Ticket 93m722, 1776 Nov. 18
  - Lottery Ticket 45m429, 1776 Nov. 18
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776 Dec. 21; Wharton, Samuel
  - Sums paid... for Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1776 Dec. 27-1780 Sept. 6; Franklin, Benjamin
  - Massachusetts. Council Deposition.., 1777 Jan. 1, 15
  - Receipted bill for Benjamin Franklin Bache's schooling for the quarter., 1777 Jan. 8; Hourville, d'
  - to ---- ----, 1777 Jan. 10; Wharton, Samuel
  - to M. Benson [Silas Deane], 1777 Jan. 14; Wharton?, Samuel
  - to France -- Accounts, 1777 Jan. 16-1778 August 12; Com.
  - to [ Benjamin Franklin?], 1777 Jan. 17; [Wharton?, Samuel]
  - Franklin's and Deane's account with Ferdinand Grand, 1777 Jan. 31-June 10
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Feb. 5; Bache, Richard (Oversize 1)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Feb. 28; Bache, Richard (Oversize 1)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 March 10; Bache, Richard
  - Agreement re packet boats, [1777 March]
  - Agreement re packet boats, [1777 March]
  - Agreement re packet boats, 1777 March
  - Packet Service Contract, 1777 April 1
  - to [James] Bowdoin, 1777 April 14; Lotbinière, Michel-Alain Chartier de
  - to Marquis de Lotbiniere, 1777 April 16; Bowdoin, James
  - 1777 April 28-May 8, Copie de correspondance.; Lotbinière, Michel-Alain Chartier de
  - Franklin's and Deane's account with Ferdinand Grand, 1777 April 28-June 10
  - to Richard Bache, 1777 May 1; Hastings, Jonathan Jr.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 June 5; Hillegas, Michael
  - Statement of accounts with the commissioners, 1777 June 10-1778 March 30; [extra-oversize, 6 sheets in 1 folder]; Grand, Ferdinand
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 June 20; Bache, Richard
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 June 20; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 July 1; Bache, Richard
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 July 4-9; Lowell, James
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 July 9; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 July 17; Hillegas, Michael
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Oct. 4; Caffiéri, Jean Jacques
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Oct. 12; Coder, -----
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Oct. 12; Ruault, Nicolas
  - Receipt from Lecoeur for Benjamin Franklin Bache's schooling for two quarters, 1777 Oct. 20
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Oct. [?] 21; La Rochefoucauld, Louis Alexandre, duc de
  - to Benjamin Franklin and Silas Deane, 1777 Oct. 26; Hennett, Françcois Auguste Pompée
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Oct. 28; Partridge, Elizabeth
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Nov. 2; Buffon, Georges Louis Leclerc, comte de, 1707-1788
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Nov. 7; Sarsfield, Guy-Claude, comte de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Nov. 8; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Nov. 14; Feutry, Aimé Ambroise Joseph
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Dec. 2; Fleury, Mme Berthérand de
  - Announcement of surrender of Burgoyne at Saratoga, 1777 Dec. 4
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Dec. 5; Faudoas, Mme de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777] Dec. 5; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Dec. 9; Bachelier, Jean Jacques
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Dec. 10; Faudoas, Mme de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [ca. 1777] Dec. 12; La Rochefoucauld, Louis Alexandre, duc de
  - to R. Morris, 1777 Dec. 20; Langdon, John
  - to Comtesse de Forbach, 1777 Dec. 28; Franklin, Benjamin
  - to ----, 1777 Dec. 29; Franklin, Benjamin
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Dec. 31; Forbach, Marianne Camasse, comtesse de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777 Dec.]; La Rochefoucauld, Louis Alexandre, duc de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777] Saturday 21; Forbach, Marianne Camasse, comtesse de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777; Filleul, Louis
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777]; Lovell, James, 1737-1814
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777?]; Melmouth, Courtney
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777]; Sarsfield, Guy-Claude, comte de
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777?]; Turgot, Anne-Robert-Jacques, baron de l'Aulne
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [ca. 1777-1778]; Unidentified correspondent
  - to unidentified recipient, 1778 Jan. 3; Unidentified correspondent
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 Jan. 3; Barbeu-Dubourg, -----
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 Jan. 8; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 Jan. 9; Collas, Jane Mecom
  - to Dubourg, 1778 Feb. 22; De Sapieha, Princesse
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 Feb. 24; Turgot, Anne-Robert-Jacques, baron de l'Aulne
  - [1778 Feb.], Barbeu-Dubourg, -----
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 March 11; Hewson, Mary Stevenson